A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files 2004-2005
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files 2004-2005
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.081
7,200 items (24 Hollinger boxes, ca. 10 linear shelf feet)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access is prohibited for ten years from the date of creation unless special permission is granted by the President's Office. Under the terms of the Virginia Freedom of Information Act (Sec. 2.1-343 (4), the records of the president or other chief executive officer of any state-supported institution of higher education are exempt from the law's access provisions.
Additional access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
These records were transferred from the Office of the President, Madison Hall, University of Virginia, through Peggy S. Pasternak, on August 14, 2008.
Scope and Content
These files constitute the major record series generated by the president of the University of Virginia, John Thomas Casteen, III, ca. 7,200 items (24 Hollinger boxes, ca. 10 linear shelf feet), 2005-2006.
The records consist chiefly of correspondence, but also include reports, minutes, clippings, memoranda, and related papers concerning all areas of business of the president's office. Major topics include American Council on Education; Association of American Universities; athletics and the NCAA; the Council of Presidents of State-Aided Institutions of Higher Learning in Virginia; development; the General Assembly; the Governor of Virginia's office; the Mariners' Museum; the Medical Center and the Health Services Foundation; Reserve Officers' Training Corps; State Council of Higher Education for Virginia; and Student Affairs.
Arrangement
Both the series and file headings used by the president's office have been retained. Restricted material has been placed in its own series. There are two series: Series I) General Files (Boxes 1-20); Series II) Restricted Files (Boxes 21-24).
Contents List
- Series I: General Files
  - A-Aq Miscellaneous 2005-1006, 14 items (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Ar-Az Miscellaneous 2005-2006, 17 items (Box-folder 1:2)
  - African-American Affairs 2006, 2 items (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Alumni Association 2005-2006, 13 items (Box-folder 1:4)
  - American Council on Education 2005-2006, 11 items (Box-folder 1:5)
  - American Council on Education Fellows 1992-1996, 17 items (Box-folder 2:1)
  - American Council on Education Fellows 1998-2000, 7 items (Box-folder 2:2)
  - American Council on Education Fellows 2001-2005, 10 items (Box-folder 2:3)
  - Applications for Positions 2005, 1 item (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Architect of the University, Office of 2005, 3 items (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Architecture, School of 2005-2006, 13 items (Box-folder 2:6)
  - Art, Department of 2005, 1 item (Box-folder 2:7)
  - Art Museum 2005-2006, 4 items (Box-folder 2:8)
  - Arts and Sciences 2005-2006, 4 items (Box-folder 2:9)
  - Association for the Accreditation of Human Research Protection Programs 2004 November-2005 August, 28 items (Box-folder 3:1)
  - Association for the Accreditation of Human Research Protection Programs 2005 September, 28 items (Box-folder 3:2)
  - Association for the Accreditation of Human Research Protection Programs 2005 November-2006 March, 13 items (Box-folder 3:3)
  - Association of American Colleges and Universities 2005-2006, 5 items (Box-folder 3:4)
  - Association of American Universities 2005, 10 items (Box-folder 3:5)
  - Association of American Universities 2006, 2 items (Box-folder 4:1)
  - Association of Governing Boards 2005-2006, 8 items (Box-folder 4:2)
  - Athletics 2005-2006, 18 items (Box-folder 4:3)
  - Athletics-Atlantic Coast Conference (ACC) 2005, 11 items (Box-folder 4:4)
  - Athletics-Atlantic Coast Conference 2006, 8 items (Box-folder 4:5)
  - Athletics-National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA) 2005-2006, 19 items (Box-folder 4:6)
  - Auditor of Public Accounts 2005, 11 items (Box-folder 5:1)
  - Ba-Be Miscellaneous 2005-2006, 14 items (Box-folder 5:2)
  - Bf-Br Miscellaneous 2005-2006, 12 items (Box-folder 5:3)
  - Br-Bz Miscellaneous 2005-2006, 8 items (Box-folder 5:4)
  - Business and Finance 2005 June-2006 February, 25 items (Box-folder 5:5)
  - Business and Finance 2006 March, 7 items (Box-folder 5:6)
  - Business and Finance 2006 April-June, 20 items (Box-folder 5:7)
  - Ca Miscellaneous-Folder 1 of 2 2005-2006, 4 items (Box-folder 6:1)
  - Ca Miscellaneous-Folder 2 of 2 2005-2006, 5 items (Box-folder 6:2)
  - Cb-Co Miscellaenous 2005-2006, 17 items (Box-folder 6:3)
  - Co Miscellaenous-Folder 1 of 3 2005-2006, 6 items (Box-folder 6:4)
  - Co Miscellaneous-Folder 2 of 3 2005-2006, 2 items (Box-folder 6:5)
  - Co Miscellaneous-Folder 3 of 3 2005-2006, 6 items (Box-folder 6:6)
  - Cp-Cz Miscellaneous 2005, 1 item (Box-folder 7:1)
  - Carr's Hill 2005-2006, 2 items (Box-folder 7:2)
  - Casteen, John T. III 2000-2005, 2 items (Box-folder 7:3)
  - Cavalier Daily 2005, 1 item (Box-folder 7:4)
  - Charlottesville 2006, 3 items (Box-folder 7:5)
  - Chesapeake Bay Foundation 2005-2006, 18 items (Box-folder 7:6)
  - Commerce, School of 2006, 1 item (Box-folder 7:7)
  - Community Relations 2005-2006, 4 items (Box-folder 7:8)
  - Condolences A-K 2005-2006, 24 items (Box-folder 7:9)
  - Condolences L-Z 2005-2006, 30 items (Box-folder 7:10)
  - Congress 2005-2006, 6 items (Box-folder 7:11)
  - Continuing and Professional Studies, School of 2005-2006, 13 items (Box-folder 7:12)
  - Council for Higher Education Accreditation 2004-2006, 7 items (Box-folder 7:13)
  - Council of Presidents (Virginia) 2005, 10 items (Box-folder 7:14)
  - Council of Presidents (Virginia) 2005-2006, 7 items (Box-folder 7:15)
  - D Miscellaneous 2005-2006, 12 items (Box-folder 8:1)
  - Darden, Joshua 2005, 4 items (Box-folder 8:2)
  - Darden School 2005, 49 items (Box-folder 8:3)
  - Darden School 2 2005-2006, 51 items (Box-folder 8:4)
  - Deans' Development Forum 2005 November 29, 21 items (Box-folder 8:5)
  - Deans' Development Forum 2005 November 29, 1 item (Box-folder 8:6)
  - Deans' Retreat 2005 August 17, 2 items (Box-folder 9:1)
  - E Miscellaneous 2005, 3 items (Box-folder 9:2)
  - Education School 2005-2006, 13 items (Box-folder 9:3)
  - Engineering and Applied Sciences School 2005, 23 items (Box-folder 9:4)
  - Engineering and Applied Sciences School 2006, 16 items (Box-folder 9:5)
  - English Department 2005, 2 items (Box-folder 9:6)
  - Equal Opportunity Programs Office 2005-2006, 3 items (Box-folder 9:7)
  - F Miscellaneous 2005-2006, 16 items (Box-folder 9:8)
  - Facilities Managment 2004-2005, 2 items (Box-folder 10:1)
  - Faculty 2005, 1 item (Box-folder 10:2)
  - Faculty Forum for Scientific Research 2005-2006, 2 items (Box-folder 10:3)
  - Fall Convocation 2005, 57 items (Box-folder 10:4)
  - Federal Relations 2005-2006, 20 items (Box-folder 10:5)
  - Finance, Vice President of 2005-2006, 22 items (Box-folder 10:6)
  - Financial Aid 2005-2006, 6 items (Box-folder 10:7)
  - G Miscellaneous 2005-2006, 5 items (Box-folder 10:8)
  - General Assembly 2005, 3 items (Box-folder 10:9)
  - General Assembly 2006, 5 items (Box-folder 11:1)
  - Governmental Relations 2005, 10 items (Box-folder 11:2)
  - Governmental Relations 2006, 10 items (Box-folder 11:3)
  - Governor's Office 2005, 19 items (Box-folder 11:4)
  - Governor's Office 2006, 19 items (Box-folder 11:5)
  - H Miscellaneous 2005-2006, 26 items (Box-folder 12:1)
  - Honor Committee 2006, 4 items (Box-folder 12:2)
  - Human Resources 2005-2006, 6 items (Box-folder 12:3)
  - Hurricane Katrina 2005-2006, 4 items (Box-folder 12:4)
  - I Miscellaneous 2005-2006, 11 items (Box-folder 12:5)
  - Institutional Assessment and Studies 2005-2006, 6 items (Box-folder 12:6)
  - International Studies 2005-2006, 12 items (Box-folder 12:7)
  - Invitations to Inaugurations 2005-2006, 23 items (Box-folder 12:8)
  - Ivy Foundation 2005, 10 items (Box-folder 13:1)
  - J Miscellaneous 2005-2006, 12 items (Box-folder 13:2)
  - Jefferson Foundation 2005-2006, 4 items (Box-folder 13:3)
  - Jefferson Park Avenue Project 2003-2006, 17 items (Box-folder 13:4)
  - Jefferson Scholars Foundation 2005-2006, 10 items (Box-folder 13:5)
  - K Miscellaneous 2005-2006, 15 items (Box-folder 13:6)
  - L Miscellaneous 2005-2006, 19 items (Box-folder 13:7)
  - Law School 2005-2006, 11 items (Box-folder 13:8)
  - Library 2005-2006, 6 items (Box-folder 13:9)
  - Ma-Mel Miscellaneous 2005-2006, 26 items (Box-folder 14:1)
  - Mem-Mz Miscellaneous 2005-2006, 11 items (Box-folder 14:2)
  - Management and Budget, Office of 2005, 12 items (Box-folder 14:3)
  - Management and Budget, Office of 2006, 7 items (Box-folder 14:4)
  - Mariners' Museum Board of Trustees 2005 August-September, 6 items (Box-folder 14:5)
  - Mariners' Museum Board of Trustees 2005 December, 8 items (Box-folder 14:6)
  - Mariners' Museum Board of Trustees 2006, 7 items (Box-folder 14:7)
  - Medical Center 2005-2006, 8 items (Box-folder 14:8)
  - Medical Center Medical School 2006, 1 item (Box-folder 14:9)
  - Medical Center Nursing School 2006, 1 item (Box-folder 14:10)
  - Na-Nd Miscellaneous 2005-2006, 10 items (Box-folder 15:1)
  - Ne-Nz Miscellaneous 2005-2006, 21 items (Box-folder 15:2)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land Grant Colleges 2005-2006, 5 items (Box-folder 15:3)
  - O Miscellaneous 2005-2006, 5 items (Box-folder 15:4)
  - Pa-Pm Miscellaneous 2005-2006, 16 items (Box-folder 15:5)
  - Po-Pz Miscellaneous 2005-2006, 12 items (Box-folder 15:6)
  - Planning 2005-2006, 3 items (Box-folder 15:7)
  - Politics 2005-2006, 5 items (Box-folder 15:8)
  - President's Cabinet 2005-2006, 8 items (Box-folder 15:9)
  - Procurement Services 2005-2006, 2 items (Box-folder 15:10)
  - Provost 2006 February-June, 16 items (Box-folder 15:11)
  - Provost Task Force on Public Policy 2005 June-August, 8 items (Box-folder 16:1)
  - Provost Task Force on Public Policy 2005 September-2006 January, 19 items (Box-folder 16:2)
  - Ra-Rg Miscellaneous 2005-2006, 9 items (Box-folder 16:3)
  - Rh-Rz Miscellaneous 2005-2006, 9 items (Box-folder 16:4)
  - Registrar 2005, 2 items (Box-folder 16:5)
  - Research, Vice President of 2005-2006, 7 items (Box-folder 16:6)
  - ROTC 2005, 2 items (Box-folder 16:7)
  - Sa-Sh Miscellaneous 2005-2006, 13 items (Box-folder 16:8)
  - Si Miscellaneous 2005, 1 item (Box-folder 16:9)
  - Sl-Sm Miscellaneous 2005-2006, 7 items (Box-folder 17:1)
  - So-Sz Miscellaneous 2005-2006, 11 items (Box-folder 17:2)
  - Semester at Sea 2005-2006, 25 items (Box-folder 17:3)
  - Senate Faculty 2005-2006, 5 items (Box-folder 17:4)
  - Society of University Families 2005-2006, 7 items (Box-folder 17:5)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools 2005-2006, 6 items (Box-folder 17:6)
  - South Lawn Project 2005-2006, 9 items (Box-folder 17:7)
  - Sponsored Programs, Office of 2006 April, 3 items (Box-folder 18:1)
  - State Council of Higher Education for Virginia 2005 July-September, 8 items (Box-folder 18:2)
  - State Council of Higher Education for Virginia 2005 September-2006 June, 9 items (Box-folder 18:3)
  - Student Affairs 2005 April-November, 16 items (Box-folder 18:4)
  - Student Affairs 2005 December-2006 June, 19 items (Box-folder 18:5)
  - Student Affairs Fraternities and Sororities 2006, 3 items (Box-folder 18:6)
  - Student Council 2005, 1 item (Box-folder 18:7)
  - Summer Session 2005-2006, 3 items (Box-folder 18:8)
  - Ta-Tn Miscellaneous 2005-2006, 5 items (Box-folder 19:1)
  - To-Tz Miscellaneous 2005-2006, 16 items (Box-folder 19:2)
  - Thomas, Clayton A., Jr. 2005, 1 item (Box-folder 19:3)
  - U Miscellaneous 2005-2006, 8 items (Box-folder 19:4)
  - United States Department of Education 2004-2006, 11 items (Box-folder 19:5)
  - University Relations 2005-2006, 12 items (Box-folder 19:6)
  - University of Virginia's College at Wise 2004-2006, 15 items (Box-folder 19:7)
  - University of Virginia Foundation 2004, 1 item (Box-folder 19:8)
  - University Press 2005, 2 items (Box-folder 19:9)
  - Vi Miscellaneous Folder 1 of 2 2005-2006, 9 items (Box-folder 20:1)
  - Vi Miscellaneous Folder 2 of 2 2005-2006, 18 items (Box-folder 20:2)
  - Valedictory Exercises 2005-2006, 3 items (Box-folder 20:3)
  - Vice Presidents' Retreat 2004-2005, 7 items (Box-folder 20:4)
  - Wa-Wh Miscellaneous 2005-2006, 13 items (Box-folder 20:5)
  - Wi-Wz Miscellaneous 2005-2006, 13 items (Box-folder 20:6)
  - Weldon Cooper Center for Public Service 2005, 2 items (Box-folder 20:7)
  - Z Miscellaneous 2006, 2 items (Box-folder 20:8)
- Series II: Restricted Materials
  - A Miscellaneous 2005, 1 item (Box-folder 21:1)
  - Admissions 2005 April-September, 13 items (Box-folder 21:2)
  - Admissions 2005 October-November, 38 items (Box-folder 21:3)
  - Admissions 2005 December-2006 January, 39 items (Box-folder 21:4)
  - Admissions 2006 February-March, 22 items (Box-folder 21:5)
  - Admissions 2006 March-April, 29 items (Box-folder 21:6)
  - Admissions 2006 April-May, 23 items (Box-folder 21:7)
  - Audit Department 2005 June-2006 February, 17 items (Box-folder 22:1)
  - Audit Department 2006 March-June, 14 items (Box-folder 22:2)
  - B Miscellaneous 2005-2006, 13 items (Box-folder 22:3)
  - C Miscellaneous 2005-2006, 4 items (Box-folder 22:4)
  - Community Relations 2005, 1 item (Box-folder 22:5)
  - Condolences 2005-2006, 16 items (Box-folder 22:6)
  - D Miscellaneous 2006, 1 item (Box-folder 22:7)
  - Darden School 2005, 4 items (Box-folder 22:8)
  - Deans' Development Forum 2005 November, 2 items (Box-folder 22:9)
  - Development 2005-2006, 2 items (Box-folder 23:1)
  - Education School 2004, 1 item (Box-folder 23:2)
  - Engineering and Applied Sciences, School of 2005, 1 item (Box-folder 23:3)
  - Equal Opportunity Programs 2005-2006, 9 items (Box-folder 23:4)
  - F Miscellaneous 2006, 1 item (Box-folder 23:5)
  - Federal Relations 2006, 1 item (Box-folder 23:6)
  - Financial Aid 2005-2006, 6 items (Box-folder 23:7)
  - G Miscellaneous 2005-2006, 2 items (Box-folder 23:8)
  - Human Resources 2005-2006, 8 items (Box-folder 23:9)
  - Institute of Shipboard Education 2005, 1 item (Box-folder 23:10)
  - International Studies 2005, 1 item (Box-folder 23:11)
  - K Miscellaneous 2005, 1 item (Box-folder 23:12)
  - Law School 2005, 2 items (Box-folder 24:1)
  - Managment and Budget, Office of 2005, 1 item (Box-folder 24:2)
  - Medical Center 2005, 1 item (Box-folder 24:3)
  - N Miscellaneous 2006 May, 1 item (Box-folder 24:4)
  - P Miscellaneous 2005-2006, 2 items (Box-folder 24:5)
  - Procurement services 2006, 1 item (Box-folder 24:6)
  - Provost 2005-2006, 4 items (Box-folder 24:7)
  - R-S Miscellaneous 2005, 6 items (Box-folder 24:8)
  - Recommendations 2005-2006, 11 items (Box-folder 24:9)
  - Student Affairs 2005-2006, 5 items (Box-folder 24:10)
  - T Miscellaneous 2006, 1 item (Box-folder 24:11)
  - University of Virginia's College at Wise 2005, 1 item (Box-folder 24:12)